Bharti Patel

UX Designer with background in Visual & Advertising

CONTACT

- **(**510) 221-8063
- bhartip0703@gmail.com
- Fremont, CA
- in linkedin.com/in/bharti7
- bhartiux.github.io

TOOLS

Adobe Creative Suite Sketch 3 InVision Axure MS Office HTML CSS Oracle Webcenter Axure RP 8

SKILLS

User research
User personas
Data synthesis
Rapid prototype
Information architecture
Usability testing
Wireframes
Service design
Visual design

EDUCATION

General Assembly

San Francisco, CA
User Experience Design
Immersive program crafted
by top practitioners in the field
-10 weeks Full time
Diploma in Commercial Arts
Nirmala Niketan, India

CERTIFICATION

Academy X - Web Design Santa Clara, CA Learn IT - Computer Graphics San Mateo, CA

PROFILE

I'm a Designer with a passion for creativity. I believe that simplicity is the ultimate sophistication – that less is more. I have an extensive background in graphic design, web design, and advertising. I bring my experience, passion, and professionalism to any creative task.

EXPERIENCE

UX/UI Designer - 12 Digit Marketing Jun 2017-Oct 2017

- Working with team to improve UI and providing right solution to the interface and, delivering pixel perfect mockups for development.
- Producing mock ups and prototypes while iterating with engineering and product management to meet feature requirements for the existing product
- Working with Client Service Manager with visual designs for Retail/Brand creative campaigns delivering responsive designs.

UX Designer & Visual Designer- Cisco Systems Jan 2017-May 2017

- Worked as one of the UX designer & Visual Designer for Cisco VTS (Virtual Topology Systems) product.
- Collaborated with service provider customers like Version and Turk Cell.
- Worked on the Visuals for VTS poster using the personas.
- Produced mock ups and prototypes while iterating with engineering and product management to meet feature requirements for the existing product.

UX Designer - Incorta April 2016-May 2016

- 3-weeks worked with Incorta that provides same-day analytics for business user & allows business to use data more quickly.
- Worked on the catalog section that needed clear and engaging interface.
- Provided solution by creating more user friendly, welcoming layout.
- User & stakeholder interviews, surveys, contextual inquiry, competitive and comparative analysis, and usability testing drove the design of the prototype.

UX Designer - San Francisco Bicycle Coalition (SFBC) March 2016-April 2016 (as part of General Assembly)

- 2-weeks project to design an mobile app that allows SFBC members to communicate and share with each other.
- User interviews, survey, competitive & comparative analysis, user flow, site maps,
- concept model, and wireframes. Usability testing drove the design of the prototype.

Bharti Patel

UX Designer with background in Visual & Advertising

CONTACT

- **(**510) 221-8063
- bhartip0703@gmail.com
- Fremont, CA
- in linkedin.com/in/bharti7
- bhartiux.github.io

TOOLS

Adobe Creative Suite Sketch 3 InVision Axure MS Office HTML CSS Oracle Webcenter Axure RP 8

SKILLS

User research
User personas
Data synthesis
Rapid prototype
Information architecture
Usability testing
Wireframes
Service design
Visual design

EDUCATION

General Assembly

San Francisco, CA
User Experience Design
Immersive program crafted
by top practitioners in the field
-10 weeks Full time
Diploma in Commercial Arts
Nirmala Niketan, India

CERTIFICATION

Academy X - Web Design
Santa Clara, CA
Learn IT - Computer Graphics
San Mateo, CA

EXPERIENCE

UX Designer - Progress Hardware -Ecommerce website March 2016 (as part of General Assembly)

- 2-weeks project to design an ecommerce website that helps to find right tool for loyal customers who don't like to go to stores, through detailed reviews, update inventory & same day shipping option.
- Used stakeholder interviews, competitive and comparative analysis, card sorting, and usability testing to inform design of global navigation as well as search and check out flows.

Web / Visual Designer- Ross Stores Inc. Dublin, CA Oct 2013- Dec 2015

- Researched & redesigned intranet portal using Adobe Creative suite & Oracle Webcenter.
- Created meaningful and compelling designs to help users become more productive and frequently visit the portal.
- Worked on design to be simpler and user friendly from complex and abstract material.
- Collaborated extensively across department & with various stakeholders.

Freelance Projects:

Web Designer - Drishticon, Fremont, CA

Dec 2014 - Mar 2015

- Worked with owner & developers to improve the UI & Visuals of their current website.
- Recreated the current logo & the banners using Adobe Illustrator & Photoshop.

Graphic/ Web Designer - Infinilytics Inc, Santa Clara, CA May 2013 - Jul 2013

- Designed marketing and promotional materials across email, mobile, web, print, and social media.
- Created branding materials logo creation and reconstruction.
- Assisted others with layout and design worked with marketing department to improve the final product.

Web Designer - Ondemandtek, Fremont, CA Jan 2009 - Mar 2009

- Worked with various design tools including Dreamweaver, Photoshop, Illustrator, and Flash to implement web designs and functionality
- Created Logo using Adobe illustrator.